<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>puerto-rico on Why Puerto Rico</title>
    <link>http://whypr.rocks/categories/puerto-rico/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in puerto-rico on Why Puerto Rico</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://whypr.rocks/categories/puerto-rico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Uber in Condado</title>
      <link>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-08-uber-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 09:25:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-08-uber-pr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uber in Condado is very quick. I rarely wait more than a couple minutes for a driver. This morning I had fun driver named
Nelson. He&amp;rsquo;s from Puerto Rico but lived in Massachusetts for 20 years. He ased how I liked living in Puerto Rico and I said it
was great. He asked why I moved to Puerto Rico and I told him it was the tax advantages.  He said he had heard about that
and he said he was very happy people are moving to Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that I should take Uber because the money stays in Puerto Rico.  If I take a Taxi then I&amp;rsquo;m giving money to the
Dominicans and they just send it back to the Dominican Republic.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that most taxi drivers were Dominicans.&lt;br /&gt;
The next time I take a taxi I&amp;rsquo;ll ask the driver where he&amp;rsquo;s from.falkj&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving into a Dual Momentum Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-04-dual-momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 07:58:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-04-dual-momentum/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantcon&#34;&gt;QuantCon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended QuantCon last week in NYC to learn about algorithmic trading. In the back of my head my goal was to come
up with a way to invest and diversify my portfolio.  QuantCon isn&amp;rsquo;t really about that as much as it is coming
up with new algorithms for trading.  But it was a good place for me to learn about investment and algorithmic investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One talk made a big impact on me. Gary Antonacci&amp;rsquo;s talk titled &amp;ldquo;Snake Oil, Swamp Land, and Factor-Based Investing&amp;rdquo;. Gary
Antonacci is a long time investor and finance geek. His talk was an overview of his book really, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0071849440/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Dual Momentum Investing: An
Innovative Strategy for Higher Returns with Lower Risk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-inital-problem&#34;&gt;The Inital Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past my approach has been to have a balanced portfolio split between stocks and bonds.  In the late 1990s and early 2000s
we moved into a diversified portfolio of stocks and municiple bonds.  Those bonds have been maturing and I haven&amp;rsquo;t really
had a lot of choice for the bonds so I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to corporate bonds but this seems too risky to me really, since it&amp;rsquo;s not
diversified, it&amp;rsquo;s all companies.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also moved to Puerto Rico (link) and so the tax advantage of bonds no longer applies
if you live here. (Is that true?  How is bond interest taxed as a PR resident?  The are taxed at the Federal level and then
also at the PR level?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most conservative advice is to have a mix of stocks and bonds, starting with &lt;sup&gt;70&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;30&lt;/sub&gt; and increasing the bonds holdings as you age.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the stock side of that portfolio first. How do you diversify? The easiset way is to simply buy index funds.
Looking at sites like Betterment, Market Riders, and Wealth Front they will do this for you, for a fee of course. The problem
with these sites is that they don&amp;rsquo;t take into account your existing portfolio with respect to taxes or diversification. They just
tell you to give them cash and they&amp;rsquo;ll deal with it.  If you have large gains, then their advice is to just sell and give them
the cash.  Sorry that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on slowly move our stock portfolio over to a handful of index ETFs. Broad ETFs will let you ride the market
trends with very little fees. I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://personal.vanguard.com/us/funds/snapshot?FundIntExt=INT&amp;amp;FundId=0970&#34;&gt;Vanguard Total Market Index
(VTI)&lt;/a&gt; The question then becomes how to do you move
out of 50 or so stocks and into a handful of ETFs? My strategy was to simply sell anyting that didn&amp;rsquo;t have a tax consequence and
then buy VTI with the proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enter-dual-momentum&#34;&gt;Enter Dual Momentum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antonacci&amp;rsquo;s approach was very appealing to me for several reasons. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, based on broad indexes, low fee, and beats the
market. Basically you move between three investments, US Stocks, European Stocks, and bonds. You make the moves monhtly based on
annual momentum. You should read the book and his blog, but the main idea is that momentum works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the chart for today. Note that S&amp;amp;P 500 (VOO) is the winner over the last year, so it has the most momentum. So if today
was your reblannce day, then you would move your portfolio 100% into VOO. If you were already there, then you would stay there.
That&amp;rsquo;s it, you just check &lt;a href=&#34;http://stockcharts.com/freecharts/perf.php?BIL,VOO,VEU&amp;amp;n=252&amp;amp;O=011000&#34;&gt;this chart&lt;/a&gt; once per month and
make the move. It should be the same time each month.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-fluid&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://whypr.rocks/assets/images/PerfChartBilVooVeu-05-04-2017.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Perfchart for May 4, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This sounds too easy, but Antonacci and other&amp;rsquo;s have done extensive backtesting. See is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.optimalmomentum.com/faq.html&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&#34;(https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0071849440/sensr-20)&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; for more
information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-to-dual-momentum&#34;&gt;Moving to Dual Momentum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to my original problem.  How do I move into this portfolio?  Since the model is telling me that I should be in
VOO right now, I&amp;rsquo;m selling my BND ETF as well as my small GLD ETF and moving those to VOO.  That part is easy.
What about that basket of stocks?  I have a set of other individual stocks that I&amp;rsquo;m going to just let ride for now.&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve held most of these stocks for a long time, Warren Buffet style, so there is no reason to sell them.  Since I have
a Puerto Rico tax decree, if I hold them for 10 years I only pay 5% tax, so unless I think the company is going to tank,
I&amp;rsquo;ll just hold them for another 8.5 years and then diversify.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>