<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Why Puerto Rico</title>
    <link>http://whypr.rocks/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Why Puerto Rico</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 09:25:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://whypr.rocks/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Uber in Condado</title>
      <link>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-08-uber-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 09:25:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-08-uber-pr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uber in Condado is very quick. I rarely wait more than a couple minutes for a driver. This morning I had fun driver named
Nelson. He&amp;rsquo;s from Puerto Rico but lived in Massachusetts for 20 years. He ased how I liked living in Puerto Rico and I said it
was great. He asked why I moved to Puerto Rico and I told him it was the tax advantages.  He said he had heard about that
and he said he was very happy people are moving to Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also said that I should take Uber because the money stays in Puerto Rico.  If I take a Taxi then I&amp;rsquo;m giving money to the
Dominicans and they just send it back to the Dominican Republic.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that most taxi drivers were Dominicans.&lt;br /&gt;
The next time I take a taxi I&amp;rsquo;ll ask the driver where he&amp;rsquo;s from.falkj&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving into a Dual Momentum Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-04-dual-momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 07:58:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whypr.rocks/post/2017-05-04-dual-momentum/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantcon&#34;&gt;QuantCon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended QuantCon last week in NYC to learn about algorithmic trading. In the back of my head my goal was to come
up with a way to invest and diversify my portfolio.  QuantCon isn&amp;rsquo;t really about that as much as it is coming
up with new algorithms for trading.  But it was a good place for me to learn about investment and algorithmic investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One talk made a big impact on me. Gary Antonacci&amp;rsquo;s talk titled &amp;ldquo;Snake Oil, Swamp Land, and Factor-Based Investing&amp;rdquo;. Gary
Antonacci is a long time investor and finance geek. His talk was an overview of his book really, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0071849440/sensr-20&#34;&gt;Dual Momentum Investing: An
Innovative Strategy for Higher Returns with Lower Risk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-inital-problem&#34;&gt;The Inital Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past my approach has been to have a balanced portfolio split between stocks and bonds.  In the late 1990s and early 2000s
we moved into a diversified portfolio of stocks and municiple bonds.  Those bonds have been maturing and I haven&amp;rsquo;t really
had a lot of choice for the bonds so I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to corporate bonds but this seems too risky to me really, since it&amp;rsquo;s not
diversified, it&amp;rsquo;s all companies.  I&amp;rsquo;ve also moved to Puerto Rico (link) and so the tax advantage of bonds no longer applies
if you live here. (Is that true?  How is bond interest taxed as a PR resident?  The are taxed at the Federal level and then
also at the PR level?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most conservative advice is to have a mix of stocks and bonds, starting with &lt;sup&gt;70&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;30&lt;/sub&gt; and increasing the bonds holdings as you age.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the stock side of that portfolio first. How do you diversify? The easiset way is to simply buy index funds.
Looking at sites like Betterment, Market Riders, and Wealth Front they will do this for you, for a fee of course. The problem
with these sites is that they don&amp;rsquo;t take into account your existing portfolio with respect to taxes or diversification. They just
tell you to give them cash and they&amp;rsquo;ll deal with it.  If you have large gains, then their advice is to just sell and give them
the cash.  Sorry that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on slowly move our stock portfolio over to a handful of index ETFs. Broad ETFs will let you ride the market
trends with very little fees. I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://personal.vanguard.com/us/funds/snapshot?FundIntExt=INT&amp;amp;FundId=0970&#34;&gt;Vanguard Total Market Index
(VTI)&lt;/a&gt; The question then becomes how to do you move
out of 50 or so stocks and into a handful of ETFs? My strategy was to simply sell anyting that didn&amp;rsquo;t have a tax consequence and
then buy VTI with the proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enter-dual-momentum&#34;&gt;Enter Dual Momentum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antonacci&amp;rsquo;s approach was very appealing to me for several reasons. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, based on broad indexes, low fee, and beats the
market. Basically you move between three investments, US Stocks, European Stocks, and bonds. You make the moves monhtly based on
annual momentum. You should read the book and his blog, but the main idea is that momentum works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the chart for today. Note that S&amp;amp;P 500 (VOO) is the winner over the last year, so it has the most momentum. So if today
was your reblannce day, then you would move your portfolio 100% into VOO. If you were already there, then you would stay there.
That&amp;rsquo;s it, you just check &lt;a href=&#34;http://stockcharts.com/freecharts/perf.php?BIL,VOO,VEU&amp;amp;n=252&amp;amp;O=011000&#34;&gt;this chart&lt;/a&gt; once per month and
make the move. It should be the same time each month.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-fluid&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://whypr.rocks/assets/images/PerfChartBilVooVeu-05-04-2017.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Perfchart for May 4, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This sounds too easy, but Antonacci and other&amp;rsquo;s have done extensive backtesting. See is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.optimalmomentum.com/faq.html&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&#34;(https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0071849440/sensr-20)&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; for more
information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-to-dual-momentum&#34;&gt;Moving to Dual Momentum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to my original problem.  How do I move into this portfolio?  Since the model is telling me that I should be in
VOO right now, I&amp;rsquo;m selling my BND ETF as well as my small GLD ETF and moving those to VOO.  That part is easy.
What about that basket of stocks?  I have a set of other individual stocks that I&amp;rsquo;m going to just let ride for now.&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve held most of these stocks for a long time, Warren Buffet style, so there is no reason to sell them.  Since I have
a Puerto Rico tax decree, if I hold them for 10 years I only pay 5% tax, so unless I think the company is going to tank,
I&amp;rsquo;ll just hold them for another 8.5 years and then diversify.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year In</title>
      <link>http://whypr.rocks/post/one-year-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 23:14:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://whypr.rocks/post/one-year-in/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been living in Puerto Rico for a bit over a year now.  Why did we do it and how is it working out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initally we were interested because of the potential tax savings. If you live off of investments, then you
can avoid paying capital gains tax on your investments if you live in Puerto Rico. Tech entrepreneurs make
their money by creating companies and selling the stock in those companies.  If you have a big win, then you
also have a big tax bill. It&amp;rsquo;s attractive to think about having another big exit and not having to pay taxes
on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, we started exploring the idea of moving to Puerto Rico and we found that we love the island
and the people here.  &lt;em&gt;We came for the tax breaks and we stayed for the people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-ve-made-a-ton-of-new-friends&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve made a ton of new friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puerto Rico is a friendly place. Part of it is the culture and part of it is a result of meeting like minded people.
Yes, compared to &lt;strong&gt;The States&lt;/strong&gt; Puerto Rico has a lot of issues.  There&amp;rsquo;s the government debt.  There are infrastructure
issues.  Crime and beggars can be an issue.  More on that later, but let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the people first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;loving-the-locals&#34;&gt;Loving the locals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve made a bunch of local friends.  We&amp;rsquo;ve found that Puerto Ricans are super friendly.  When you first arrive you
mainly deal with service industry people like taxi drivers, hotel clerks, and waiters and waitresses.  The taxis aren&amp;rsquo;t
so great, but the rest of the folks seemed very open to giving us advice and answering our questions.  What worked
for us was to get involved in things we already liked to do, and we met folks through those activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;tennis&#34;&gt;Tennis&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a huge tennis center at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.palmasdelmar.com/v2/index.php&#34;&gt;Palmas Del Mar&lt;/a&gt; about 45 minutes from San Juan.&lt;br /&gt;
We started there and met some of our first and best friends in Puerto Rico.  Palmas is a great place to live if you
want to keep a boat nearby or even in back of your house.  The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.palmaspac.com/&#34;&gt;Palmas Athletic Club&lt;/a&gt; includes
the tennis center, which is largest in the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In San Juan there are lots of great places to play tennis too.  Here are a few other favorites. &lt;a href=&#34;http://islaverdetennis.com/index.html&#34;&gt;The Isla Verde Tennis&lt;/a&gt;
club is just a few miles from the airport.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.globaltennisnetwork.com/tennis-courts/courts/tennis-court-page/court/25192-ocean-park&#34;&gt;Ocean Park&lt;/a&gt; has great courts right next to the beach.  There is also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tennisround.com/pr/tennis-courts/san-juan/rio-piedras/club-de-san-francisco-24809&#34;&gt;San Francisco Tennis Club&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.globaltennisnetwork.com/tennis-courts/courts/tennis-court-page/court/39230-baldrich-club-de-tenis&#34;&gt;Baldrich Tennis Club&lt;/a&gt; in Hato Rey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;tech-startups&#34;&gt;Tech Startups&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a tech entrepreneur so went in search of co-working spaces and found &lt;a href=&#34;http://piloto151.com/&#34;&gt;Piloto 151&lt;/a&gt; in
Old San Juan.  It&amp;rsquo;s a great place to hangout and they have regular activities for learning and networking.  They
were running a &lt;a href=&#34;https://fi.co&#34;&gt;Founder&amp;rsquo;s Institute&lt;/a&gt; program when I arrived and I ended up getting involved in that as a
mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very lucky that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parallel18.com/&#34;&gt;Parallel 18&lt;/a&gt; was just starting when I moved here. This is an accellerator
program that is nurturing a tech startup ecosystem here in Puerto Rico.  They help startups from Puerto Rico and all
over the world take the next step in building their busineses.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been a mentor for the first two cohorts and found
it a to be a very exciting program and a great place to meet like minded people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;meetups&#34;&gt;Meetups&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/&#34;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; had a lot of activities where we could meet new people. For Puerto Rico
tech folks, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/San-Juan-Tech-Meetup/&#34;&gt;San Juan Tech Meetup&lt;/a&gt; is a great one to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-nuvo-ricans&#34;&gt;The Nuvo Ricans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to help stimulate the economy, Puerto Rico passed some interesting tax laws to incentivize&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.the2022actsociety.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.the2022actsociety.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;addressing-the-negatives&#34;&gt;Addressing the negatives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, Puerto Rico has it&amp;rsquo;s issues, but in our experience they haven&amp;rsquo;t been showstoppers and they add to some of the flavor
of the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;isn-t-the-island-bankrupt&#34;&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t the island bankrupt?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a financial crisis for sure. But frankly I don&amp;rsquo;t see the issues day to day. They still repair the streets. (Yes, there
are still a lot of huge potholes.  But drive around South of Market in San Francisco and it&amp;rsquo;s worse I think.)
I&amp;rsquo;m often amazed to see street cleaners walking around sweeping and cleaning up the town. This seems to be going on even on
holidays and weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construction seems to be going on.  Restaurants are constantly opening.  Buildings are being built.  Plaza Las Americas,
&lt;em&gt;the largest mall in the carribbean&lt;/em&gt;, is constantly busy and finding a parking space is often a challenge.  The government
may be out of cash, but the economy is still vibrant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is some strife over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/here-s-how-promesa-aims-tackle-puerto-rico-s-debt-n601741&#34;&gt;PROMESA&lt;/a&gt;. Congress has stepped in to &lt;em&gt;restructure&lt;/em&gt; the debt and put in an oversight board. They
did the same to &lt;a href=&#34;https://cityroom.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/07/25/when-new-york-teetered-on-the-brink-of-bankruptcy/&#34;&gt;New York
City&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s
and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/local/longterm/library/dc/control/controlqa.htm&#34;&gt;Washington DC&lt;/a&gt; in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the government needs to figure out how to get things back on track.  But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t effect daily life except
for the occasional protest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;doesn-t-the-electricty-and-water-go-out-all-the-time&#34;&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t the electricty and water go out all the time?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen it go out a few times.  Most buildings have generators. The super modern buildings can run for days without power.
The older bulidings have a generator that runs the elevator and maybe one outlet per apartment for the fridge.  We don&amp;rsquo;t have
snow days but there have been days when school was cancelled because of power issues.  The good news is if the power is out,
you can go sit on the beach under a palm tree.  You can drive to the other side of the island and stay in a hotel.  It&amp;rsquo;s
not more of an issue than earthquakes or epic storms that you see in other places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-you-feel-safe&#34;&gt;Do you feel safe?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are parts of San Francisco California where I don&amp;rsquo;t feel safe. There are parts of San Juan Puerto Rico that I don&amp;rsquo;t feel
safe. But generally the places where you would want to live are safe. Puerto Rico&amp;rsquo;s economy is tourism based and they do spend
funds on policing and keeping things safe. It is strange that because it&amp;rsquo;s a small island, you do have very fancy places near
government housing. Some people opt to live in gated communities and that&amp;rsquo;s an option. We have lots of friends that don&amp;rsquo;t live
in gated communities. Our building doesn&amp;rsquo;t have full time security but it&amp;rsquo;s in a tourist area and very safe. Our building is
filled will older retirees and families with young kids.  Two of the top schools on the island are across the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are beggars on the streets in certain places.  It&amp;rsquo;s nothing compared to San Francisco though.  I do choose certain
routes when driving to minimize the intersections with beggars. I like to joke that Waze should have an option for avoiding
interestions with beggars.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-fluid&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://whypr.rocks/assets/images/waze.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Fake Waze&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://welcome.topuertorico.org/aboutpr.shtml&#34;&gt;Welcome To Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt; for the banner image.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>